TYLER FORD

WEB DEVELOPER

INFO

ADDRESS

2464 Skyline Dr, Salt Lake City, 84108, United States

PHONE

4356406878

EMAIL

tylerford@gmail.com

PLACE OF BIRTH

Gilroy, CA

NATIONALITY

American

LINKS

<u>Github</u>

SKILLS

Visual Design Skills

••••

Front End Development

••••

Knowledgable in User Interface/User Experience

••••

Adaptability

••••

Strong Leadership Skills

••••

Programming

••••

Adaptability

••••

PROFILE

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in copy-writing, video production, and digital marketing, educated at the University of Utah. Skills in HTML, CSS and JavaScript and strengths in meeting deadlines, creativity and teamwork. Oversaw branded redesign of the company website, and created a branded Capital Campaign website and video that has to date raised over 4 million dollars. Excited to approach programming challenges from different angles and collaborate with others to create useful web applications. Positioned well to provide unique perspectives on how end-users interact with websites, software platforms, and emails by leveraging my background in digital marketing.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Marekting Communications Manager / Front End Designer, I.J. & Jeanné Wagner Jewish Community Center

Salt Lake City

Aug 2015 - Present

- Oversaw branded redesign of the company website, and created a branded Capital Campaign website and video that has to date raised over 4 million dollars.
- Led transition from print-heavy advertising and publications to measurable digital advertisements, and consistent mobile-friendly e-newsletters and donation forms.
- Developed meaningful content to build engagement including hundreds of original videos, gifs, and photographs.
- Worked well independently and within a team setting.

Public Relations Associate, Tanner Humanities Center Oct 2014 - Jul 2015

Salt Lake City

- Coordinated all aspects of monthly National Theater Live film screenings including program selection & scheduling, promotion, production, ticketing database management, and reporting.
- Managed front-end development for company website.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.

EDUCATION

University of Utah, Bachelor of Cinema Arts

Salt Lake City

Aug 1999 - May 2010

COURSES

Full Stack Developer Boot Camp, University of Utah

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

Web Design Tools, University of Utah

Apr 2012 - Jul 2012

REFERENCES

References available upon request